Bill Bahlman Papers GLBTQ.1998.01
GLBTQ Archives
Bill Bahlman Papers
1986-1998
GLBTQ.1998.01
GLBTQ Archives
1.0 Linear feet
William (Bill) Bahlman is an activist and journalist, working since the 1970's to fight for access to medications for all people with HIV and AIDS and to document this fight through photography and videography. He is currently associate producer for a weekly news program of GLBTQ interest and serves on AIDS research advisory boards, while living with HIV since the 1980's. This collection includes copies of flyers Mr. Bahlman created for AIDS advocacy campaigns, AIDS-related newspaper articles, and selected testimony before Presidential and Congressional Commissions.
Biographical/Historical note
William (Bill) Bahlman is a long-term activist and journalist. A member of the Gay Activists Alliance in the 1970s, Bill Bahlman was a co-founder of both the Lavender Hill Mob and ACT UP New York. He served on the Issues Committee of ACT UP which tirelessly studied every aspect of drug development and of the government’s response to HIV/AIDS. Mr. Bahlman served on countless community, government and industry advisory boards fighting for expanded access and faster development of life saving drugs. He was news director and co-anchor of “Out in the 80’s / 90’s” and is currently associate producer of Gay USA, a weekly hour of news, analysis and interviews. Bill Bahlman is also an accomplished photographer and videographer. His work appears in two AIDS documentary films; “Testing the Limits” and the 2012 Oscar nominated film by director David France “How to Survive a Plague;” he appears in France’s film as a community reporter and as a treatment advocate from ACT UP New York. Mr. Bahlman was diagnosed as HIV-positive in 1989.
Scope and Contents note
The Bill Bahlman Papers are almost totally AIDS related. They include early flyers from the Lavender Hill Mob and from ACT UP, New York City. There are copies of testimony before the Presidential Commission on AIDS (1987-88) and of Congressional testimony. There are some photocopies of AIDS related newspaper articles. The range of materials includes copies of flyers, newspaper articles, statements and testimony before Senate and Congressional committees.
Bahlman, William (Bill); Acquired Immunodeficiency Syndrome -- history; ACT UP (AIDS Coalition to Unleash Power); AIDS (Disease) -- Political aspects; AIDS (Disease) -- Research; AIDS (Disease) -- Treatment; AIDS activists; Health Policy -- history; HIV Infections -- history; HIV-positive persons; New York (State) -- New York; New York City
- Bill Bahlman Papers at the National Archive of Lesbian and Gay History, New York, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Lavender Hill Mob, news release and flyer, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- "Mob Zaps Grant", reprint, New York Native, 12/22/86 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- a) Protest at St. Patrick's Cathedral against Arch-Bishop John O'Connor by the Lavender Hill Mob, announcement, November 2, 1986 b) "Bishop's Conference Mum on Vatican Letter, Hunthausen", reprint, Washington Blade, November 14, 1986 c) "The Lavender Hill Mob Zaps the Cardinal", reprint, New York Native, November 17, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- "River Hotel Negotiations Falter", reprint, New York Native, October 6, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- "Bringing Back the Zap", reprint, New York Native, December 22, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- "Center for Disease Control to Throw out Civil Liberties.", announcement, flyer, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- "Test Drugs, Not People", flyer, announcement regarding a meeting of the Center for Disease Control, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- "Hypocrisy and the Roman Catholic Church", flyer, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- "Real People, Real Lives", announcement of the Lavender Hill Mob to rally against Archbishop John O'Connor, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- "Real People, Real Lives", handout, Pro-Choice Demonstration, Bryant Park, New York City, January 1987 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- a)"Massive Aids Demonstration", flyer, announcement of a meeting on Wall Street at Trinity Church, Tuesday, March 24 at 7:00 a.m. b) "Massive AIDS Demonstration", flyer, announcement of ACT UP (The AIDS Coalition to Unleash Power) meeting, Tuesday, March 31, 208 West 13th St. c) "Massive AIDS Demonstration", flyer, announcement of a meeting at the Gay and Lesbian Community Center, 208 West 13th St., Thursday, March 19 at 7:30 p.m. (Box 1, Folder 12)
- "Wall Street Chants", flyer, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- "Donahue and AIDS Activists", leaflet announcing talk show guests, Wednesday, April 1 [1987] (Box 1, Folder 14)
- "Demand That Your Tax Dollars Be Spent on AIDS Research!”, flyer, announcement ACT UP, April 15 [1987] (Box 1, Folder 15)
- a) "Lavender Hill Mob Makes Bold New Proposal on Experimental Drugs", "Reagan Cabinet Officer Zapped by the Mob”, press releases, April [1987] b) "Education Secretary Says 'Just Say No to Education'", leaflet by the Lavender Hill Mob, [1987] c) "Test Drugs, Not People", leaflet, [1987] (Box 1, Folder 16)
- a) " Institutional Stagnation plus Prejudice Equals Death", testimony of the Lavender Hill Mob entered into the Congressional Record, House Committee on Human Resources and Intergovernmental Operations, April 29, 1987 b) "The Congress and the Senate Must Right The Wrong!", leaflet of the Lavender Hill Mob, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- "Are You Now or Have You Ever Been Seropositive?", leaflet of the Lavender Hill Mob denouncing federal AIDS testing, [1987] (Box 1, Folder 18)
- "Reagan Administration Says: 'Just Say No to Education.'”, flyer, The Lavender Hill Mob, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 19)
- The Lavender Hill News, newsletter of the Lavender Hill Mob, May 1987 (Box 1, Folder 20)
- "Stand for Medicine and Science”, flyer, Lavender Hill Mob, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 21)
- "National AIDS Demonstration at the White House", flyer, ACT UP (AIDS Coalition to Unleash Power), 1987 (Box 1, Folder 22)
- "Test Drugs, Not People", "Institution Stagnation plus Prejudice Equals Death", flyer, Lavender Hill Mob, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 23)
- "AIDS Politics and Prejudice", flyer in English and Spanish, ACT UP, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 24)
- "Is the Government Playing with Politics?", flyer, Lavender Hill Mob and ACT UP, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 25)
- "The Government's Real Policy on AIDS", flyer, announcement, ACT UP, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 26)
- "Making Mob Scenes and Street Theater", news release, In These Times, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 27)
- "If It's Not Medicine, it’s Murder", flyer, Lavender Hill Mob, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 28)
- "AIDS: Politics and Prejudice”, flyer, Lavender Hill Mob, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 29)
- "La Administracion Reagan Dice", flyer in Spanish by ACT UP, [1987] (Box 1, Folder 30)
- a) "To The Staff of Memorial Sloan-Kettering and Other Area Hospitals", flyer, 1987 b) "A Fact Sheet", information on ATEUs (AIDS Treatment Evaluation Units), 1987 (Box 1, Folder 31)
- "AIDS and America: A case study in dementia", flyer, Lavender Hill Mob, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 32)
- a) "Robertson Joins the Fray", news release, Washington Post, 1987 b) "Pat Robertson: Health Policy of a Lunatic", announcement, ACT UP, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 33)
- "The NIH and AIDS: So you think they are looking for a cure?", fact sheet, ACT UP, speaking against Dr. Anthony Fauci and Dr. Robert Gallo, Interscience Conference of Microbial Agents and Chemotherapy [1987] (Box 1, Folder 34)
- a) “The Reagan AIDS strategy in ruins", news release, The New York Times, Sunday, 1987 b) “Can the world rely on U.S. leadership on AIDS?", fact sheet, ACT UP, October 1987 (Box 1, Folder 35)
- "Agitate, Educate, Organize", ACT UP, announcement, registration 1987 (Box 1, Folder 36)
- "Secretary of Education William Bennett says 'Just say No to education'", flyer, ACT UP, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 37)
- a) "An Appeal to People of Science and Reason", flyer, Lambda Center of Dental Health, [1987] b) "What: Aids Die-In Demonstration Where: New York City Department of Health and City Hall”, announcement, ACT UP, 1987 c) "Money for Aids", flyer, announcement of march on City Hall, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 38)
- "What is the drug so useful that Frank Young dare not speak its name?", fact sheet on the FDA and the Treatment IND protocol, [1987] (Box 1, Folder 39)
- "False Hope: Smoke and Mirrors from the FDA”, reprint P I Perspective, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 40)
- "AIDS, Drugs and $$$$$", flyer re: meeting of the President's Commission on AIDS, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 41)
- "A call for the removal of the intravenous placebo in the IVIG trial for HIV-infected children" (Intravenous Immunoglobulin), fact sheet, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 42)
- "What Does IMREG Value More?", fact sheet on experimental drug ' IMREG -1'and Treatment IND, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 43)
- "AIDS In New York City", fact sheet from ACT UP documenting city health Commissioner Stephen C. Joseph's failure to effectively deal with the AIDS epidemic [1987] (Box 1, Folder 44)
- a) "Mario, Your 'Family' Has AIDS”, flyer, ACT UP, n.d. b) "NBC Policy On AIDS: To Frighten Or Enlighten?", flyer, announcement, ACT UP, 1987 c) " ACT UP presents Teach-In Issues", meeting announcement, ACT UP, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 45)
- “The U.S. Health Summit On HIV Offers No Hope For People With Aids", flyer condemning the Public Health Service, ACT UP, [1988] (Box 1, Folder 46)
- "The Lavender Hill News", mock-up, January 1, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 47)
- “The Lavender Hill News Premier Issue”, January 1, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 48)
- “The Lavender Hill News”, April 1987 (Box 1, Folder 49)
- “The Lavender Hill News”, May 1987 (Box 1, Folder 50)
- "Support AIDS Activism! SUPPORT ACT UP!", flyer, announcement, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 51)
- a) "Wider use of experimental drug for AIDS ailment is approved", reprint New York Times, 1988 b) "Whose protocol?", reprint Village Voice, 1988 c) "U.S. to allow wider distribution use of Warner-Lambert AIDS-related drug", reprint Wall Street Journal, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 52)
- Gay Pride Issue- The Lavender Hill News, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 53)
- Speech by Gary L. Bauer, Assistant to the President for Policy Development, White House National Conference on HIV/AIDS., November 18, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 54)
- a) The U.S. Health summit on HIV offers no hope for people with AIDS", announcement, ACT UP, [1988] b) "AIDS anti-bias statute debated", reprint Newsday, 1988 c) A brief summary of ACT UP's participation in the U.S. Health Summit on HIV infection, fact sheet, ACT UP, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 55)
- a) "ACT UP summary of the U.S. Health Summit on HIV infection, 1988", report prepared by Bill Bahlman of ACT UP December 1988 b) "Summary of U.S. Health Summit on HIV and ACT UP's actions", typed copy sent to Chris Bull from Bill Bahlman, December 1988 c) "ACT UP New York invites itself to closed AIDS meeting", article by Chris Bull in Gay Community News, December, 1988 d) The U.S. Public Health Service, flyer announcing U.S. Health Summit on HIV Infection 1988 (Box 1, Folder 56)
- a) Dr. Lilly, Woodrow A. Myers, M.D., John Cardinal O'Connor, Penny Pullen, fact sheet by ACT UP, [1989], gives background of the above named people b) "AIDS: A Presidential Issue”, article by Woodrow A. Myers, reprinted from The Wall Street Journal, December 30, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 57)
- Protest and disruption of Mass at St. Patrick’s Cathedral, New York, flyers, articles, December 1989 (Box 1, Folder 58)
- "ACT UP = ACTION!!", checklist of criteria needed to start an action, includes several sample flyers and announcements, ACT UP, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 59)
- "Atlanta Planning Committee: The CDC definition of AIDS is not a bureaucratic issue, it is a medical and political issue, fact sheet, ACT UP, November, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 60)
- a) "Officials traced Typhoid Mary", article by Fern Shumer Chapmen, reprint, USA Today, 1989 b) Debate: "Help stop AIDS with contact tracing", Bill Bahlman, an opposing view, reprints, USA Today, December, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 61)
- a) The City Of New York Comptroller's Report, Volume 14, Number 2, August, 1988 b) The City Of New York Comptroller’s Report, Volume 14, Number 3, September 1988 c) The City Of New York Comptroller's Report, Volume 14, Number 4, October 1988 d) "He who laughs last", article by Christopher M. Finan, reprint Playboy, 1988 e) "Recommendations of the Presidential Commission on HIV involving basic research, vaccine and drug development the White House has disagreed with", fact sheet, ACT UP, 1989 f) "Booksellers speak out against pending federal anti-pornography legislation", quotations compiled by Bill Bahlman, 1989 g) "Talking Points" The Child Protection and Obscenity Enforcement Act of 1988 h) "Notice! Your rights to read and view whatever you choose are under attack by the U.S. Justice Department”, pamphlet, fact sheet, ACT UP, n.d. i) "The Honorable Peter Rodino, Chairman of the House Judiciary Committee," form letter to be sent in opposition to legislation sponsored by Mr. Hughes (HR03889) and Mr. Green (HR 1213), n.d. j) "The Honorable Joseph Biden, Chairman of the Senate Judiciary Committee", form letter to be sent in opposition to legislation sponsored by Senator Thurmond, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 62)
- "HR 2881 An Act to Establish a National Commission on Acquired Immune Deficiency Syndrome", August, 1987, reprint (Box 1, Folder 63)
- a) "Assembly Bill No. 1952, California State Legislature, March 6, 1987”, bill specifying the creation of the AIDS Vaccine Research and Development Committee b) "State authority to approve new drug applications: An analysis of the California AIDS drug testing initiative”, copy of paper written by Margaret McCarthy for Columbia Law School, December, 1987 c) "Experimental AIDS drug testing in humans approved by state senate", reprint Los Angeles Times, n.d. d) "Governor gets bill to permit experimental tests of AIDS drugs", reprint Los Angeles Times, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 64)
- a) State of New York Public Health Council, minutes of meeting, January, 1988 b) "Health department blames prostitutes for AIDS", fact sheet, announcement of public health council codes committee meeting, ACT UP, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 65)
- a) Human Rights Campaign Fund, copy of list of co-sponsors, n.d. b) Human Rights Campaign Fund, copy of legislative agenda, n.d. c) Human Rights Campaign Fund, fact sheet prepared by ACT UP, n.d. d) Human Rights Campaign Fund Update: AIDS legislation, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 66)
- "ACT UP demonstrators were attacked by angry republicans during a Reagan rally at the New Orleans convention center on August 14, 1988, reprint PGN (The Philadelphia Gay News), 1988 (Box 1, Folder 67)
- Interview with Senator Hatch September 2 [1988] on CBS Morning News (Box 1, Folder 68)
- Peter Staley, articles, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 69)
- Press clippings from American and Canadian press, June, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 70)
- a) "Should laws require notification of AIDS victims’ contacts?" reprinted from USA Today, Sept. 15, 1982 b) "Help stop AIDS with contract tracing", "AIDS contact tracing won't halt this disease", opposing view by Bill Bahlman, USA Today, Tuesday, December 12, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 71)
- "Understanding AIDS", pamphlet published by the U.S. Department of Health and Human Services, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 72)
- "Rice, revolution and soon to be homeless", Bill Bahlman writes to his fellow ACT UP members for personal financial help, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 73)
- "Relationship between fetal tissue research and the search for treatments for people with AIDS", discussion with members of the treatment and data committee of ACT UP transcribed by Bill Bahlman, news director of the Gay Broadcasting System, articles resulting from the broadcast in News Day, New York Times, The Washington Post, November, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 74)
- "Revolution recalled", voices from The Stonewall Generation, announcement of a forum held at the Lesbian & Gay Community Services Center, NY, June, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 75)
- ACT UP treatment and data files, list of AIDS-related drugs listing chemical origins, date of first use, includes list of AIDS drug-related news articles (Box 1, Folder 76)
- "The rise of militant AIDS activism", reprint outlining some of the militant activism that preceded ACT UP and provided an impetus for their founding, November, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 77)
- a) Public hearing schedule, Presidential commission on the HIV epidemic, January, 1988 b) Biographical information, Presidential commission on the HIV epidemic, January, 1988 c) Research hearings contact list d) Research hearings, lists specific meetings, dates and times and location (Box 1, Folder 78)
- a) "77 products in research or already developed for AIDS, pharmaceutical industry tells commission." news release, Pharmaceutical Manufacturers Association, February, 1988 b) Gerald J. Mossinghoff, Pharmaceutical Manufacturers Association, statement before President's Commission on HIV epidemic, New York, Pharmaceutical Manufacturers Association, February, 1988 c) Dr. G. B. Rathmann, President Amgen Inc., chairman of the Industrial Biotechnology Association, statement to the Presidential AIDS Commission, February, 1988 d) Pattrick Gage, Ph.D., Vice President for Exploratory Research, Hoffmann-La Roche Inc., statement before the Presidential Commission on the HIV epidemic, New York, February, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 79)
- a) "Public health observations derived from the multicenter AIDS cohort study of homosexual men.” presented by Harold M. Ginzburg, M.D., before Presidential Commission on HIV, January, 1988 b) Clinic/Office Care testimony presented by Dr. Gerald Friedland, to Presidential Commission on HIV, January, 1988 c) Testimony at care hearings, Dr. Paul Auerbach, to Presidential Commission on HIV, January, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 80)
- a) "Virus Epidemic: Community Nursing Organizations”, by Susan K. Riesch, DNSC RN to Presidential Commission on HIV, January, 1988 b) Statement of Joseph McCarthy to Presidential Commission on HIV, January, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 81)
- a) Testimony describing the establishment of the HIV center for clinical and behavioral studies at Columbia Presbyterian Medical Center by Esther Chachkes, to Presidential Commission on HIV, January, 1988 b) Testimony of Judy L. Spinella, case hearing and recommendations to Presidential Commission on HIV, January, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 82)
- a) The AIDS epidemic and not for profit hospitals, testimony of Richard N. Yezzo, to Presidential Commission on HIV, January, 1988 b) Testimony of Dennis Andrulis, to Presidential Commission on HIV, January, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 83)
- Testimony by Cliff Morrison, Deputy Director the Robert Wood Johnson Foundation, to Presidential Commission on HIV, January, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 84)
- a) Testimony of Dr. Susan Tross, psychologist at Memorial Sloan Kettering Cancer Center, to Presidential Commission on HIV, January, 1988 b) Testimony of Joel R. Gray, LPN, nursing student, University Of Iowa, person with ARC (AIDS related complex) before the Presidential Commission on the HIV epidemic health care hearings, January, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 85)
- a) Statement of Edward D. Barrett, M.S., D.D.S. to Presidential Commission on the Human Immunodeficiency Virus Epidemic, January, 1988 b) Statement of Vincent C. Rogers, D.D.S., M.P.H., American Dental Association, to the President's Commission on AIDS, January, 1988 c) Recommendations to the President's Commission on AIDS by William M Mitchell, M.D., Ph.D., professor of Pathology, Vanderbilt University, Nashville, Tennessee, n.d. d) Care needs of HIV infected women and families, by Howard L. Minkoff, M.D., Director of Obstetrics and Maternal Fetal Medicine, SUNY, Health Science Center Of Brooklyn, New York, January, 1988 e) Testimony of Virginia M. Jackson, C.N.M., Nurse Midwife on staff of North Central Bronx Hospital, New York City to Presidential Commission on HIV, January, 1988 f) Statement Of Audrey F. Manley, M.D., M.P.H., Director, National Health Service Corps, Bureau of Health Care Delivery and Assistance, U.S. Public Health Service, Department of Health and Human Services to Presidential Commission on HIV, January, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 86)
- Testimony by Vivien De Back, Ph.D., R.N., Project Director, National Commission on Nursing Implementation Project to Presidential Commission on HIV, January, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 87)
- Statement of Senator Edward M. Kennedy on the Emergency Aids Relief Legislation, March 6, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 88)
- Metro system schedule, airline and bus schedules plus map of Washington, D.C. area, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 89)
- a) "The FDA, Kids, AZT + ddI", remarks by Bruce Chabner, M.D., Division of Cancer Treatment, National Cancer Institute, January, 1989 b) "Retrovir available to children under treatment”, news release, Burroughs Wellcome Co., October, 1989 c) "AZT Treatment for babies”, by Laurie Garrett, reprint New York Newsday, October, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 90)
- “Retrovir approved for asymptomatic/early symptomatic HIV-infected patients", news release, Burroughs Wellcome, March, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 91)
- a) "Burroughs Wellcome reaps profits, outrage from its AIDS drug”, by Marilyn Chase, Wall Street Journal, September, 1989 b) "AZT: A windfall for pharmacies?", article, Drug Topics, September, 1987 c) "Why you should boycott Burroughs Wellcome", "How you can boycott Burroughs Wellcome”, flyer, n.d. d) Position statement on renewal of federal funding for AZT, American Association of Physicians for Human Rights, July, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 92)
- "Wellcome unit gets U.S. patent for AIDS drug", reprint Wall Street Journal February, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 93)
- "AIDS as a sexually transmitted disease", testimony by Michael J. Rosenberg, M.D., M.P.H. Executive Director, American Social Health Association, September, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 94)
- Interview between Bill Bahlman and Kristine Gebbie, member of the Presidential Commission on HIV, May, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 95)
- "Public Health Officials, do your jobs!", by Penny Pullen, member of the Presidential Commission on the HIV Epidemic, reprint The New American, May, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 96)
- Letter from Kenneth T. South, Consultant to Dr. Frank Lilly of the Presidential Commission on the Human Immunodeficiency Virus Epidemic, January, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 97)
- a) Presidential Commission on HIV, Health Care Worker Safety, notes and impressions by Bill Bahlman, May, 1988 b) Hearings on the safety of the blood supply, the Presidential Commission on HIV, May, 1988, notes by Bill Bahlman c) Additional notes by Bahlman on the blood supply hearings, May, 1988 d) Hearings on AIDS in the workplace, notes and impressions by Bill Bahlman, May, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 98)
- Presidential Commission on HIV, notes and impressions by Bill Bahlman, May, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 99)
- Program of the panel discussions, Presidential Commission on the Human Immunodeficiency Virus Epidemic, May, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 100)
- Presidential Commission International Hearings, April, 1988, notes and impressions by Bill Bahlman (Box 1, Folder 101)
- "International efforts in AIDS research at the National Institutes of Health " Statement of Karl A. Western, M.D., D.T.P.H., Assistant Director for International Research, National Institute of Allergy and Infectious Diseases, before the Presidential Commission on the Human Immunodeficiency Virus Epidemic, April, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 102)
- "HIV screening and its use in public health”, by Professeur A. Pompidou, Counsellor for the French Ministry of Health, Coordinator for National AIDS Program, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 103)
- a) “AIDS panel getting to the big issues”, article by Lori Olszewski, San Francisco Chronicle, March, 1988 b) “Commission tours S.F. General, AIDS panel hears pleas for funds”, by Lori Olszewski, San Francisco Chronicle, [March, 1988] c) “Dukakis visits California”, article by Carl Irving, San Francisco Chronicle, March, 1988 d) “Agnos says White House fails on Aids”, article by Lisa M. Frieger, San Francisco Examiner, March, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 104)